myessentia.com 2013-05-24

# Privacy Policy for MyEssentia.com Website.

[Home](http://www.myessentia.com/) » [Customer Service](http://www.myessentia.com/customer-service/) » **Privacy Policy**

**Our Privacy Commitment**  
We at Essentia understand the importance of protecting personal information. This privacy policy outlines our guidelines for the collection and use of personal information by Essentia.

**What Information does Essentia Collect and How is it Used?**  
Essentia collects 2 types of information, personal information and non-personal information.

Only with your consent we may use your information for different purposes for example:  
• fulfill requests for services, products, or information  
• provide customer care services  
• administer promotions or contests  
• offer new products and services and  
We may also collect customer information for statistical purposes only which no longer identifies the custom.

Personal information may include your name, address, phone number, and e-mail address.

Non-personal information does not identify you as an individual. For example, we may ask you for your zip/postal code to assist us with planning our marketing campaigns.

**Your Implied Consent**  
You consent is implied when, for a stated purpose, you’re asked for personal information. For example, delivery of the product you have purchased can only be completed if you your address and phone number are provided to us.

**Your Express Consent**  
In other cases, we’ll ask you to grant your consent for use of your personal information to advise you of products or services that may be of interest. You’ll always be able to "opt out" of having your information used for these purposes.  
Withdrawing Your Consent

If you have "opted in" or subscribed to one of our newsletters or mailing lists, we will always provide you the opportunity to "opt out" or unsubscribe. For example, each e-mail we send you will tell you how to decline further e-mail.

**Information Essentia Collects from You**  
Listed here are some examples of the ways that we collect information about you and how we use it.

**Our Web Sites**  
While using our Website, you may be asked to provide certain personal information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, or credit card information voluntarily. This information is used to complete your transaction as well as apply for access to certain special features and functions of the Website. If you select not to provide the requested personal information, you will be unable to utilize certain Website features and you will be unable to engage in transactions through our Website.

With any of the services on our Websites, we may also use your personal information to contact and communicate with you and to respond to your inquiries. With your consent, we might send to you an email, from time to time or other communications regarding goods or services we believe may be of interest to you.

All references to our Website in this Policy means either Essentia.

**Participate in a Contest, Promotion, or Survey**  
At times we may run surveys, contest or promotions. If you choose to participate, questions for your contact information as well as optional survey information may be asked. Information retained from contest entries will be used to contact you if you win. We may also summarize survey information in a manner that no longer identifies the contest entrants for analysis, but will not share personal information from entries. Each specific contest will be subject to rules and regulations.

**Information Essentia Collects Automatically**  
Like most websites, we automatically collect some non-personal information regarding. Website users Examples include your IP address, the date(s) you visit, the Internet URL of the website previously visited, the operating system you are using, the sections of Essentia you visited, the Website pages read, images viewed, and content download from the Website. This non-personal information is used for to improve our services.

**Cookies**  
Cookies are used on almost all websites. Cookies are small pieces of information left on your computer which allow our Website to recognize you. Cookies improve the convenience and use of the Website. For example, cookies can be used to recognize you as a previous user of the Web Site so you wont have to enter your contact information every time or to track your activity on the Website and to facilitate your overall Website experience. Cookies are optional and can be disabled depending on your web browser. If disabled it may affect your Website use such as access certain features involving website transactions.

**Tracking Information**  
The use of non-personal information may be used for statistical analysis such as Website traffic patterns, Website purchases and then allow our advertisers and others to view such reports. The tracking information in these reports cannot be connected to the identities or other personal information of individual users. Tracking information may be linked with personal information voluntarily provided by Website users. All of the linked information is treated as personal information and will be used and disclosed only in accordance with this Policy.

**Links to Other Web Sites**  
Our Website may link to other Internet resources or Websites. When you click on those links you are contacting another Website or Internet resource. Essentia has no responsibility or liability for or control over those other Websites or Internet resources or their collection, use and disclosure of your personal information.

Please you to read the privacy policies of these other sites to find out how they collect and use information about you.

**Does Essentia Disclose the Information it Collects?**  
Your personal information is at no time sold by Essentia. However we may share your information with third parties acting on our behalf or as permitted or required by law.

**Disclosure to Service Providers**  
Essentia may share your personal information with certain service providers in order to provide products and services to you, to verify and validate information, and to address customer service matters. Examples of service providers include credit card issuers, product service depots, warranty providers, and delivery services. To reduce the risk of fraud or misuse of personal information, Essentia may also verify your personal information, including but not limited to your address and credit card information, with third party service providers.

We will use reasonable efforts to ensure that your personal information is used in a manner that is consistent with this Policy. If you do not wish us to provide your personal information to those service providers, we may be unable to process your transaction.

**Legal Disclosure**  
Essentia may disclose your information as permitted or required to by law; for example:  
• to a government institution or other person or entity that has asserted its lawful authority to obtain the information;   
• where we have reasonable grounds to believe the information could be useful in the investigation of unlawful activity;  
• to comply with a subpoena or warrant or an order made by a court, person or entity with jurisdiction to compel the production of information;  
• to comply with court rules regarding the production of records and information; and  
• to our legal counsel.

**How does EssentiaDiret Protect My Information?**  
The security of your personal information is a high priority for Essentia. We maintain appropriate safeguards and current security standards to protect your personal information, whether recorded on paper or captured electronically, against unauthorized access, disclosure, or misuse.

Although we cannot take responsibility for any theft, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, loss, alteration or destruction of data by a third party, we take reasonable precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences.

**How Can I Verify My Information?**  
You can check your information to verify, update, or correct it, and to have any obsolete information removed. If you created an account on Essentia.ca you can access and change your online personal information.  
You can also ask to review any of the information that we have retained, how we have used it, and to whom we have disclosed it at any time by contacting us at privacymanager@myessentia.com. Subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law, and provided we can authenticate your identity, you will be given reasonable access to your personal information, and will be entitled to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and to have it amended as appropriate.  
You can also ask us to change your preferences regarding how we use or disclose your information, or let us know that you do not wish to receive any further communication from us.

**When is My Information Removed?**  
We keep your information only as long as we need it for the products and services you're using and for a reasonable time thereafter or to meet any legal requirements. We have retention standards that meet these requirements. We destroy your information when it is no longer needed, or we remove your personally identifiable information.

You can also request that we remove your information from our records. Subject to our requirements for continued retention of your information, for example, for billing, audit, or warranty purposes, we will make every reasonable effort to honor your request.

**How Can I Contact Essentia?**  
Essentia is responsible for all personal information under its control. Our Privacy Manager is accountable for Essentia’s compliance with the principles described here. If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about the privacy policies please contact us at the below:

Call us at: 1-450-688-8111  
Write us at: Essentia  
Attention: Privacy Manager  
2760 Blvd. Daniel Johnson  
Laval, QC H7P 5Z7

We will respond to your request or investigate your concern as quickly as we can.

**Will this Privacy Policy Change?**  
To accommodate changes in our service, the technology, and legal developments, this Policy may change over time. We may add, change, or remove portions of this Policy when we feel it is appropriate to do so. Whenever we update this Policy we will change the date on the Policy to indicate when the changes were made.
